There can only be ONE!
Gangster No. 1 is a action, drama, thriller film directed by Paul McGuigan.
An old gangster is advised that Freddie Mays would
leave jail after thirty years in prison.
His mood changes and he recalls when he was a young punk and who joined
Freddie's gang—a man he both envied and ultimately betrayed.
Younger Gangster, played by Paul Bettany.
Gangster 55, played by Malcolm McDowell.
Freddie Mays, played by David Thewlis.
Lenny Taylor, played by Jamie Foreman.
Karen, played by Saffron Burrows.
Tommy, played by Kenneth Cranham.
Gangster No.
1 is a 2000 British crime drama film directed by Paul McGuigan.
It is based on the stage play Gangster No.1 written
by Louis Mellis and David Scinto.
The film stars Paul Bettany in the title role and features
Malcolm McDowell, David Thewlis and Saffron Burrows.
The film explores themes of prison, casino, forgiveness, gangster, repayment.
The tone is emotional and intense.